Register of the Leopold Labedz papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Conferences File, 1954-1987
  - The Department of State Research Council, 1975 (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - Détente Conference, 1975 (Box-folder 39: 2)
  - The East-West Round Table, 1984 (Box-folder 39: 3)
  - European American Institute for Security Research, 1980 (Box-folder 39: 4)
  - The European Association for Cultural Affairs: Disrupted Dialogue, 1985 (Box-folder 39: 5)
  - European-Atlantic Group, undated (Box-folder 39: 6)
  - European Freedom Council Conference, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 39: 7)
  - European Seminar, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 39: 8)
  - The First SEERG Briefing, 1985 (Box-folder 39: 9)
  - Foundation for Defence Studies, 1985 (Box-folder 39: 10)
  - The Great Britain USSR Association, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 39: 11)
  - Helsinki Conference, 1973-1985 (Box-folder 39: 12)
  - Hudson Institute, 1985 (Box-folder 39: 13)
  - The Implementation of the Final Act of the Conference on Security and Co-operation in Europe, 1975 (Box-folder 40: 1-2)
  - Indiana University - Russian and East European Institute, 1976 (Box-folder 40: 3)
  - Institute for Contemporary Studies, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 40: 4)
  - Institute for European Defence and Strategic Studies, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 40: 5)
  - Institute of Jewish Affairs, 1969-1987 (Box-folder 40: 6)
  - Institute for the Study of the USSR, 1966-1986 (Box-folder 40: 7)
  - International Conference of Officers and Officials, 1967, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 40: 8)
  - International Conference on World Peace, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 40: 9)
  - International Cultural Foundation, 1977 (Box-folder 40: 10)
  - International Institute for Strategic Studies, 1969-1985 (Box-folder 40: 11, 41: 1-3)
  - The International Parliamentary Groups for Human Rights in the Soviet Union, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 41: 4)
  - International PEN (Poets, Essayists, Novelists) Congress, 1965-1975 (Box-folder 41: 5)
  - International Security Council, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 41: 6)
  - Japan Cultural Forum: Tokyo Seminar, 1972 (Box-folder 42: 1-2)
  - London School of Economics, 1954-1985 (Box-folder 42: 3)
  - Der Monat, 1961 (Box-folder 42: 4)
  - National Republican Institute for International Affairs, 1985 (Box-folder 42: 5)
  - NATO Symposium: Colloque Colloquium, 1975 (Box-folder 42: 6-7)
  - Polish Writers Congress, undated (Box-folder 42: 8)
  - Rome Conference, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 43: 1)
  - The Royal Institute of International Affairs, 1957-1980 (Box-folder 43: 2)
  - Salzburg Symposium, 1967 (Box-folder 43: 3)
  - Salzburg Seminar in American Studies, 1975 (Box-folder 43: 4)
  - Seminar on Comparative Communists Societies, 1972 (Box-folder 43: 5)
  - The Soviet Challenge in the 1980s, 1981 (Box-folder 43: 6)
  - Soviet Historiography Conference, 1961 (Box-folder 43: 7-9, 44: 1-6, 45: 1-4)
  - Soviet Literature, 1917-1962 (Box-folder 45: 5-6, 46: 1-6, 47: 1-6, 48: 1-2)
  - Stanford, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 48: 3)
  - Stanford Colloquium on Europe's Identity, 1976 (Box-folder 48: 4)
  - Stichting Comite Vladimir Boekovski, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 48: 5)
  - Szkoła Nauk Politycznych i Społecznych, 1961 (Box-folder 48: 6)
  - VIDCCA Conference, 1971 (Box-folder 48: 7)
  - West-European Left, 1974-1978 (Box-folder 48: 8-9)
  - The White House - Human Rights Day, 1986 (Box-folder 48: 10)
  - Workshop on Poland After the Ninth Party Congress, 1981 (Box-folder 49: 1)
  - Zurich Conference, 1970 (Box-folder 49: 2)
    Refer to Box 143 for corresponding sound recordings from the conference. Additionally, notebook in Box 133, Folder 1 includes notes relating to the conference.
  - XXth Congress of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union, 1956 February 16 (Box-folder 49: 3)
  - The VIIIth Congress of the Polish United Workers Party, 1980 (Box-folder 49: 4)
  - IVth World Congress of Sociology, 1959 (Box-folder 49: 5)
  - Vth World Congress of Sociology, 1962 (Box-folder 49: 6)
  - VIIIth World Congress of Sociology, 1974 (Box-folder 49: 7)
  - XIth World Congress of Sociology, 1985 (Box-folder 47: 8)
  - VIIIth World Media Conference, 1985 (Box-folder 47: 9)
  - Conferences by year, 1959-1987
    A selection of conference materials organized chronologically by Labedz.
    - 1959-1967 (Box-folder 49: 10-18)
    - 1968-1978 (Box-folder 50: 1-12)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 50: 13)
    - 1985-1987 (Box-folder 50: 14-16)
- Radio and Television File, 1940-1988
  Contains materials such as news talks, broadcast transcripts, research materials, and reports. Includes materials that specifically focus on the British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) and Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty (RFE/RL).
  - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), 1958-1986
    - Current affairs talks, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 51: 1)
    - European service general news talk, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 51: 2-3)
    - European service general news talk, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 51: 4-6)
    - External broadcasting - current affairs talks, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 51: 7-12)
    - External services talks and features, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 51: 13)
    - International Communist front organisations, 1970 October (Box-folder 51: 14)
    - Retrospective, 1959-1968 (Box-folder 51: 15)
    - "A Story of Our Time,", 1970 (Box-folder 51: 16)
    - Summary of World Broadcasts, 1972 August 3 (Box-folder 51: 17)
  - Board for International Broadcasting, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 51: 18)
  - B-Wire, 1984 (Box-folder 51: 19)
  - CBS (Columbia Broadcasting System) television services, 1970 (Box-folder 51: 20)
  - Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, 1940-1988
    Includes administrative records, broadcast transcripts from the Special Programs series and Facts and Views series, memoranda, press surveys, and reports.
    - Administrative, 1961-1986 (Box-folder 51: 21)
    - Background information, USSR, 1957-1962 (Box-folder 52: 1-2)
    - Broadcast transcripts, 1970 (Box-folder 52: 3)
    - Broadcast transcripts, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 52: 4-6)
    - Broadcast transcripts, 1985 (Box-folder 52: 7-8)
    - Broadcast transcripts, 1986 (Box-folder 53: 1-2)
    - Broadcast transcripts (general), 1969-1988 (Box-folder 53: 3)
    - Broadcast transcripts - RFE special series, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 53: 4)
    - Bulgarian press survey, 1963 (Box-folder 53: 5)
    - Conferences, 1985 (Box-folder 53: 6)
    - Czechoslovak press survey, 1957-1962 (Box-folder 53: 7)
    - Daily Information Bulletin, 1962 (Box-folder 53: 8)
    - Hungarian press survey, 1957-1965 (Box-folder 53: 9)
    - Jan Nowak-Jeziorański, 1940-1975 (Box-folder 53: 10)
    - Memoranda, 1971-1986 (Box-folder 54: 1)
    - Monitoring material of Czechoslovak radio stations, 1968 August 23-24 (Box-folder 54: 2-3)
    - Polish press summary, 1968-1975 (Box-folder 54: 4-5)
    - Polish press survey, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 54: 6)
    - Printed matter, 1957-1985 (Box-folder 54: 7)
    - Quarterly operational report, 1975 (Box-folder 54: 8)
    - Research and evaluation department, 1962 (Box-folder 55: 1)
    - Research materials, 1957-1974 (Box-folder 55: 2)
    - "Soviet History: Yesterday and Tomorrow?,", 1964 (Box-folder 55: 3)
    - "Two Years After Khrushchev Fall: A Retrospect and Prospects,", undated (Box-folder 55: 4)
  - Rai Radiotelevisione Italiana: Servizio Stampa, 1969 (Box-folder 55: 5)
  - Warsaw Radio First and TV, 1980 (Box-folder 55: 6)
- Speeches and Writings, 1954-1996
  Various writings authored by Labedz, including a sampling of his handwritten notes. When possible, Labedz's original order was maintained.
  - "Adam Schaff - The Proud Recidivist,", 1988 (Box-folder 55: 7-8)
    Includes a Polish translation, "Dumny Recydywista."
  - "Alexander Werth and the Story of a Correspondence,", 1967-1968 (Box-folder 55: 9)
  - "Appreciating Milosz,", undated (Box-folder 55: 10)
  - "Attitudes Towards Death,", 1976 Spring (Box-folder 55: 11)
  - "The Background to Helsinki,", undated (Box-folder 55: 12)
  - "A Bad Bed Fitter,", undated (Box-folder 55: 13)
  - "Bloody Thursday in Gdynia" (translation), 1970 December 17 (Box-folder 55: 14)
  - "A Case of R. W. Johnson,", 1984 (Box-folder 55: 15)
  - "Censorship Articles,", 1977 (Box-folder 55: 16)
  - "China, USSR, and the West,", undated (Box-folder 55: 17)
  - "Chomsky Revisited,", 1980 (Box-folder 55: 18)
  - "Communism After Czechoslovakia,", 1968 (Box-folder 55: 19)
  - "Communism in Crisis,", 1968 May 24 (Box-folder 55: 20)
  - "Correspondence Book,", undated (Box-folder 55: 21)
  - "Culture in the Soviet State,", undated (Box-folder 55: 22)
  - "Czechoslovakia and After,", 1968 October (Box-folder 55: 23)
  - "Daily Telegraph: Chernenko Gets His Chance,", 1984 February 14 (Box-folder 56: 1)
  - "'Dangerous Thoughts': The Mihajlow Case: A Yugoslav Look at Russia,", undated (Box-folder 56: 2)
  - "The Destiny of Writers in Revolutionary Movements,", 1972 (Box-folder 56: 3)
  - "Détente, Culture, and Human Rights,", 1973 July 12 (Box-folder 56: 4)
  - "Détente; An Evaluation,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 56: 5)
  - "Détente - Success or Failure?,", circa 1975 (Box-folder 56: 6)
  - "Deutscher as Historian and Prophet,", 1962 (Box-folder 56: 7)
  - Discussion transcripts, circa 1960 (Box-folder 56: 8)
    Includes roundtable discussion transcripts regarding the Sino-Soviet rift. Featured speakers include: Rockingham Gill, Geoffrey Hudson, David Floyd, Richard Burks, Leonard Schapiro, and Gordon Burroughs.
  - "Dissent and Censorship,", undated (Box-folder 56: 9)
  - "Dictionary of Modern Thought,", undated (Box-folder 56: 10-12)
  - "Dictionary of Modern Thought,", 1974 (Box-folder 57: 1)
  - "Dictionary of Modern Thought," correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 57: 2)
  - "Dictionary of Modern Thought," final text with corrections, undated (Box-folder 57: 3)
  - "Draft of Letter of Invitation,", undated (Box-folder 57: 4)
  - "Dramatic Meeting of Writers,", undated (Box-folder 57: 5)
  - "Dwa Oblicza,", undated (Box-folder 57: 6)
  - "East and West: An Introspective Survey,", 1955-1977 (Box-folder 57: 7)
  - Encounter, Kennan piece, 1978 (Box-folder 57: 8)
  - Encounter piece, 1982 (Box-folder 57: 9)
  - "The End of an Epoch,", 1965 (Box-folder 57: 10)
  - "Epilogue,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 57: 11)
  - "False Dilemmas, Real Alternatives,", 1980 (Box-folder 57: 12)
  - "The French Communist Party: Its Strategy and Tactics, Its Dilemmas and Prospects,", undated (Box-folder 57: 13)
  - "From Helsinki to Belgrade,", 1976 (Box-folder 57: 14)
  - "The Future in the Past,", circa 1984 (Box-folder 57: 15)
  - The Great Purges, book review, undated (Box-folder 58: 1)
  - "The Harvest of Two Decades: The End of De-Stalinization,", undated (Box-folder 58: 2)
  - Hearing with Leopold Labedz, 1973 July 12 (Box-folder 58: 3)
    Includes opening statement of Senator Henry M. Jackson from the meeting of the Permanent Subcommittee on Investigation. Hearing focused on the Soviet views of détente and peaceful coexistence.
  - "The Highlights of the Italian Communist Party History,", undated (Box-folder 58: 4)
  - "Homage to Boris Souvarine,", circa 1978 (Box-folder 58: 5)
  - "How Europe Fell,", undated (Box-folder 58: 6)
  - "The Illusion of SALT,", 1979 (Box-folder 58: 7)
  - "International Communism after Khrushchev,", 1965 (Box-folder 58: 8)
  - "The International Scene in the Seventies,", 1973 Spring (Box-folder 58: 9)
  - "The Italian Communist Party Highlighted,", 1978 March 3 (Box-folder 58: 10)
  - "Introduction to Kolakowski,", 1968 (Box-folder 58: 11)
  - "Khrushchev's New Party History,", 1959 October 12 (Box-folder 58: 12)
  - "Labedz o Aleksandrze Wacie,", undated (Box-folder 58: 13)
  - "Labedz on Gorbachev's Accession to Power,", 1985 (Box-folder 58: 14)
  - "A Last Critique,", undated (Box-folder 58: 15)
  - "Lenin's Centenary,", 1970 Winter-Spring (Box-folder 58: 16)
  - Leo's exchange with Gladwyn in Encounter, 1981 August-November (Box-folder 58: 17)
  - Leo's major pieces edited by Melvin Laskey, 1987 (Box-folder 58: 18)
  - Leo, short articles, circa 1981 (Box-folder 58: 19)
  - Leopold Labedz replies, 1984 (Box-folder 58: 20)
  - Leopold Labedz writes, undated, 1961 (Box-folder 59: 1)
  - "The Lessons of History,", 1970 (Box-folder 59: 2)
  - "A Letter from Leopold Labedz to Shepard Stone,", 1970 June (Box-folder 59: 3)
  - "Letter to Andrzej Zagozda" (translation), 1982 August 11 (Box-folder 59: 4)
  - "Literary Development in the USSR,", undated (Box-folder 59: 5)
  - "Literature and Revolution: Writers' Destiny in Revolutionary Movements,", undated (Box-folder 59: 6)
  - "The Literature of the Western World: Anew,", 1970 (Box-folder 59: 7)
  - "Lowenthal v.s. Labedz,", circa 1984 (Box-folder 59: 8)
  - "Midweek Commentary: Russia's Thrust to the South,", 1979 August 14 (Box-folder 59: 9)
  - "A Mid-Year Report of Follies and Fallacies,", 1984 (Box-folder 59: 10)
  - "Myths and Fables,", undated (Box-folder 59: 11)
  - "The New Left,", 1970 (Box-folder 59: 12)
  - "Nixon's Moscow Visit,", 1972 May 17 (Box-folder 59: 13)
  - "The Non-Orwellian Nightmare,", 1979 (Box-folder 59: 14)
  - "Notatki o 'Majowej Rewolucji,'", undated (Box-folder 59: 15)
  - "A Note on the Soviet Handling of the Problem of Atomic Radiation,", undated (Box-folder 59: 16)
  - Notes, 1969, undated (Box-folder 59: 17, 60: 1-3)
  - "Notes and Topics: A World about Milosz,", undated (Box-folder 60: 4)
  - "Odprężenie, kultura, i prawa człowieka,", undated (Box-folder 60: 5)
  - "Of Myths and Horrors,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 60: 6)
  - "On czyli Gra Schaffa,", undated (Box-folder 60: 7)
  - "On Thermonuclear Coexistence,", 1961 (Box-folder 60: 8)
  - "The Party, Intelligentsia, and Education in the Soviet Union,", undated (Box-folder 60: 9)
  - "The Path Ahead to Europe,", 1971 (Box-folder 60: 10)
  - "Pierwsze Słowa Niezrozumiałe,", undated (Box-folder 60: 11)
  - Poems, circa 1961 (Box-folder 60: 12)
  - "Poland: From Poznan to Gdansk,", undated (Box-folder 60: 13)
  - "Poland - A Very Different Protest,", undated (Box-folder 60: 14)
  - "Poland's Stormy Petrel: Marek Hlasko and the Revolt against 'Socialist Realism,'", undated (Box-folder 60: 15)
  - "The Polish New Reformers,", undated (Box-folder 60: 16)
  - "La Psychologie de la Détente,", undated (Box-folder 61: 1)
  - Quarterly Notes, 1969 Winter-Spring (Box-folder 61: 2)
  - "A Question of Survival,", undated (Box-folder 61: 3)
  - "Raymond Aron: The Left and the Fable of Europe,", undated (Box-folder 61: 4)
  - "Red or Black,", 1971 January 14 (Box-folder 61: 5)
  - "Reply to Surkov and Aliger,", circa 1960 (Box-folder 61: 6)
  - "Revisionism," edited by Leopold Labedz, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 61: 7)
  - "Revolutionary, Statesman, Monster,", 1973 (Box-folder 61: 8)
  - "Rival Perspectives,", undated (Box-folder 61: 9)
  - "Rozmowa z Leopoldem Labedziem,", undated (Box-folder 61: 10)
  - "Rozmowy z Rosyjskimi dysydentami,", undated (Box-folder 61: 11)
  - "Russia After Khrushchev,", 1956 (Box-folder 61: 12)
  - "Russia's Drive to the South,", undated (Box-folder 61: 13)
  - "SALT II (Strategic Arms Limitation Talks) - The Political and Historical Perspective,", undated (Box-folder 61: 14)
  - "Science and the Soviet System,", 1977-1978 (Box-folder 61: 15)
  - "Shadows over Helsinki,", 1973 June (Box-folder 61: 16)
  - "The Sino-Soviet Conflict,", 1965 (Box-folder 61: 17)
  - "Sociologists in Conference,", undated (Box-folder 61: 18)
  - "Sociology and Communism,", 1957-1958 (Box-folder 61: 19)
  - "Some Reflections on Soviet Problems Today,", undated (Box-folder 61: 20)
  - "Some thoughts about 'R's' Column,", 1979 August 10 (Box-folder 61: 21)
  - "Solzhenitsyn: A Documentary Record,", 1970-1971 (Box-folder 62: 1)
  - "Soviet Attitudes Towards Sociology,", circa 1960 (Box-folder 62: 2)
  - "Soviet Foreign Policy: Looking Back To The Future,", 1978 (Box-folder 62: 3)
  - "Soviet History in Retrospect,", undated (Box-folder 62: 4)
  - "Soviet Satellites: New Stage of Integration,", 1954 (Box-folder 62: 5)
  - "The Soviet Social Science,", undated (Box-folder 62: 6)
  - "The Soviet Union in Asia,", 1972 November (Box-folder 62: 7)
  - "The Soviet Union, Communism and the Western Crisis,", undated (Box-folder 62: 8)
  - "The Soviet Union and Western Europe,", 1973 Summer (Box-folder 62: 9)
  - "Stalin and History: Perspective in Retrospective,", 1978-1979 (Box-folder 62: 10)
  - "Stalin and the World Communist Movement,", undated (Box-folder 62: 11)
  - "The State of Soviet Science,", 1966 (Box-folder 62: 12)
  - "The Structure of the Soviet Intelligentsia,", circa 1980 (Box-folder 62: 13)
  - "Struggle for Africa,", undated (Box-folder 62: 14)
  - "Students and Revolution,", 1968 (Box-folder 62: 15)
  - “Świat w Latach Siedemdziesiątych,”, 1973 (Box-folder 62: 16)
  - "A Toast to Orwell,", undated (Box-folder 62: 17)
  - “Transkrypt rozmowy: Leopold Labedz i Antoni Słonimski,”, 1974 (Box-folder 62: 18)
  - "Twenty Years After,", 1996 January (Box-folder 62: 19)
  - "The Two Minds of George Kennan,", 1978 April (Box-folder 63: 1)
  - "Under Political Blinkers: A Rejoinder to Richard Lowenthal,", undated (Box-folder 63: 2)
  - "Under Western Eyes,", undated (Box-folder 63: 3)
  - "USA and the World Today: Kissinger and After,", 1976 Winter (Box-folder 63: 4)
  - "USA and the World Today: The View from Abroad,", 1976 February 20-22 (Box-folder 63: 5)
  - "The Western Press and the Human Rights Problem,", undated (Box-folder 63: 6)
  - "What Is (Soviet) History,", circa 1970 (Box-folder 63: 7)
  - "Will George Orwell Survive 1984?,", 1984 Summer (Box-folder 63: 8-9)
  - "A Word About Milosz,", undated (Box-folder 63: 10)
  - "The 22nd Party Congress in Perspective,", undated (Box-folder 63: 11)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 63: 12)
    Includes fragments of some of Labedz's writings.
- Subject File, 1860-1987
  Original order was retained in the majority of this series.
  - Agriculture, circa 1950 (Box-folder 64: 1)
  - Alexander Herzen Foundation, undated (Box-folder 64: 2)
  - Alliluyeva, Svetlana, 1967 (Box-folder 64: 3)
  - Amalrik, Andrei, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 64: 4)
  - Bartoszewski, Wladislaw, 1975 (Box-folder 64: 5)
    Includes photocopies of certificates and diplomas.
  - Belgian League for the Defense of the Rights of Man, 1967 November (Box-folder 64: 6)
  - "Brief History of Marxist Parties in Ceylon,", 1964 July 8 (Box-folder 64: 7)
  - Bromke, Adam, undated (Box-folder 64: 8)
  - Bukovsky, circa 1969 (Box-folder 64: 9)
  - Carr, E. H., Times Literary Supplements, circa 1980 (Box-folder 64: 10)
  - Censorship in Poland, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 64: 11)
  - Chiaromonte, Nicola, 1972 (Box-folder 64: 12)
  - Church-state relations, Poland, 1980 (Box-folder 64: 13)
  - Communist party statistics, 1905-1956 (Box-folder 64: 14)
  - Copyright protection in USSR, 1973 (Box-folder 64: 15)
  - Czechoslovak intellectuals, 1968 (Box-folder 64: 16)
  - Détente, 1975 (Box-folder 64: 17)
  - Drukier, Boleslaw, undated (Box-folder 64: 18)
  - "Five Aspects of Communism,", 1974 (Box-folder 64: 19)
  - Forum briefing, China, 1967 (Box-folder 64: 20)
  - "From Political Prisoner Ivan Oleksiyovych Kandyba,", 1961 (Box-folder 64: 21)
  - Gibson, Richard, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 65: 1)
  - Ginzburg, Alexander Arkadyevich, undated (Box-folder 65: 2)
  - "History of the People's Democracies,", undated (Box-folder 65: 3)
  - Hochhuth, Rolf, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 65: 4)
  - "Hypothetical Trend of the Soviet Population and Vital Statistics,", 1860-1960 (Box-folder 65: 5)
  - "India's Divided Communist Struggle for Supremacy,", 1964 September (Box-folder 65: 6)
  - Instituto Affari Internazionali, 1971 (Box-folder 65: 7)
  - "The International Communist Conflict,", undated (Box-folder 65: 8)
  - "The International Sakharov Hearing,", 1975 (Box-folder 65: 9)
  - Jan Hus Educational Foundation, 1986 (Box-folder 65: 10)
  - Kalabinski, Jacek, case, 1961-1985 (Box-folder 65: 11)
  - Korean Airlines flight 007, 1983 (Box-folder 65: 12)
  - Kuznetsov, Anatoly, 1969 (Box-folder 65: 13)
  - Lisiecka, Alicja, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 65: 14)
  - Letter from camp number 17, Dubravnyy Directorate of Corrective Labour Camp, undated (Box-folder 65: 15)
  - Louis, Victor, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 65: 16-17)
  - Martial law in Poland, 1982 December 13 (Box-folder 65: 18)
  - Mihajlov, Mihajlo, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 65: 19)
  - Moscow Olympics, 1935-1980 (Box-folder 65: 20)
  - Mykhaylo Horyn's closing statement, closed trial held by the Lvov Region Court, 1966 April 16 (Box-folder 65: 21)
  - "The New Soviet Plan,", 1860-1960 (Box-folder 65: 22)
  - Oil crisis, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 66: 1)
  - Petition from Suyatoslav Yosypovych Karavanskyy, undated (Box-folder 66: 2)
  - "The Plot to Kill the Pope,", circa 1980 (Box-folder 66: 3)
  - Poles in USSR, 1974 (Box-folder 66: 4)
  - Polish ambassador at Oxford, 1970 (Box-folder 66: 5)
  - Polish fanfare, "Sto lat,", 1976 (Box-folder 66: 6)
  - Polish United Workers Party, 1979 (Box-folder 66: 7)
  - Polish Workers Defense Committee, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 66: 8)
  - Polish Workers Defense Committee/human rights in Poland, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 66: 9-12)
  - "Program of the Democratic Movement of the Soviet Union etc.,", 1970 (Box-folder 66: 13)
  - "Programs of the Endowment and Its Institutes in Poland,", 1987 (Box-folder 66: 14)
  - Repression in Poland, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 66: 15)
  - Riots in Radom, Ursus, 1981 (Box-folder 67: 1)
    Includes photographs.
  - Samizdat materials, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 67: 2-3)
  - Sinyavsky, undated (Box-folder 67: 4)
  - Slogans, Brussels, 1975 (Box-folder 67: 5)
  - Socials conditions, Russia, circa 1950 (Box-folder 67: 6)
  - Solidarity movement, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 67: 7)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Alexander, 1962-1971 (Box-folder 67: 8)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Alexander (A Documentary Record), circa 1970 (Box-folder 67: 9-10)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Alexander (A Documentary Record), circa 1970 (Box-folder 68: 1-3)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 68: 4)
  - Soviet objectives in the Middle East, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 68: 5)
  - Soviet theories, 1956 (Box-folder 68: 6)
  - Statement in connection with the Moscow trial against Galanskov, Ginsburg, Dobrovolskiy, and Lashkova, 1968 January 12 (Box-folder 68: 7)
  - Statistics, 1955 (Box-folder 68: 8)
  - "The Strategic Balance at Geneva,", 1962-1982 (Box-folder 68: 9)
  - Strokata, Nina, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 68: 10)
  - Strzelecki, Jan, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 68: 11)
  - Terrorism, circa 1985 (Box-folder 68: 12)
  - Ukrainian information service, 1967 (Box-folder 68: 13)
  - Voinovich, Vladimir, 1980 (Box-folder 68: 14)
  - Warsaw Ghetto Uprising, circa 1980 (Box-folder 68: 15)
- Survey File, 1905-1987
  Administrative and financial records of the journal.
  - Administrative records, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 69: 1)
  - Authors inquiring about status of manuscript, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 69: 2)
  - Background and history, 1969 (Box-folder 69: 3)
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies, Soviet project, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 69: 4)
  - Contributors, undated (Box-folder 69: 5)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 69: 6)
  - Degras, Jane, 1905-1973 (Box-folder 69: 7)
  - Direct-mail promotion, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 69: 8)
  - Exchange ads: not agreed, 1960-1965 (Box-folder 69: 9)
  - Financial records, 1965-1987 (Box-folder 69: 10)
  - Financial records, budget foundations, 1981 (Box-folder 69: 11)
  - Ford Foundation, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 69: 12)
  - Ford Foundation, assessment of Survey, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 69: 13)
  - Foreign Press Information Report: "Survey of the Soviet Press,", circa 1966 (Box-folder 69: 14)
  - Free Interprofessional Association of Workers (SMOT), 1984 (Box-folder 69: 15)
  - Fundraising and promotional campaign, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 70: 1)
  - Information Bulletin Ltd., 1973-1978 (Box-folder 70: 2)
  - Guidelines for article admission, undated (Box-folder 70: 3)
  - International Association for Cultural Freedom, 1962-1978 (Box-folder 70: 4)